(Laughter) It's easy to think so, especially when we see a few prominent examples that dominate the conversation. Well, it turns out, in the long run, they don't. There's really rich research on this by Morgan McCall and Michael Lombardo when they were at the Center for Creative Leadership. They found that the number one reason tied to executive failure was an insensitive, abrasive or bullying style. There will always be some outliers that succeed despite their incivility. Sooner or later, though, most uncivil people sabotage their success. For example, with uncivil executives, it comes back to hurt them when they're in a place of weakness or they need something. People won't have their backs. But what about nice guys? Does civility pay? Yes, it does. And being civil doesn't just mean that you're not a jerk. Not holding someone down isn't the same as lifting them up. Being truly civil means doing the small things, like smiling and saying hello in the hallway, listening fully when someone's speaking to you. Now, you can have strong opinions, disagree, have conflict or give negative feedback civilly, with respect. Some people call it "radical candor," where you care personally, but you challenge directly. So yes, civility pays. In a biotechnology firm, colleagues and I found that those that were seen as civil were twice as likely to be viewed as leaders, and they performed significantly better. Why does civility pay? Because people see you as an important -- and a powerful -- unique combination of two key characteristics: warm and competent, friendly and smart. In other words, being civil isn't just about motivating others. It's about you. If you're civil, you're more likely to be seen as a leader. You'll perform better, and you're seen as warm and competent. But there's an even bigger story about how civility pays, and it ties to one of the most important questions around leadership: What do people want most from their leaders? We took data from over 20,000 employees around the world, and we found the answer was simple: respect. Being treated with respect was more important than recognition and appreciation, useful feedback, even opportunities for learning. Those that felt respected were healthier, more focused, more likely to stay with their organization and far more engaged. So where do you start? How can you lift people up and make people feel respected? Well, the nice thing is, it doesn't require a huge shift. Small things can make a big difference. I found that thanking people, sharing credit, listening attentively, humbly asking questions, acknowledging others and smiling has an impact. Patrick Quinlan, former CEO of Ochsner Health [System], told me about the effects of their 10-5 way, where if you're within 10 feet of someone, you make eye contact and smile, and if you're within five feet, you say hello. He explained that civility spread, patient satisfaction scores rose, as did patient referrals. Civility and respect can be used to boost an organization's performance. When my friend Doug Conant took over as CEO of Campbell's Soup Company in 2001, the company's market share had just dropped in half. Sales were declining, lots of people had just been laid off. A Gallup manager said it was the least engaged organization that they had surveyed. And as Doug drove up to work his first day, he noticed that the headquarters was surrounded by barbwire fence. There were guard towers in the parking lot. He said it looked like a minimum security prison. It felt toxic. Within five years, Doug had turned things around. And within nine years, they were setting all-time performance records and racking up awards, including best place to work. How did he do it? On day one, Doug told employees that he was going to have high standards for performance, but they were going to do it with civility. He walked the talk, and he expected his leaders to. For Doug, it all came down to being tough-minded on standards and tenderhearted with people. For him, he said it was all about these touch points, or these daily interactions he had with employees, whether in the hallway, in the cafeteria or in meetings. And if he handled each touch point well, he'd make employees feel valued. Another way that Doug made employees feel valued and showed them that he was paying attention is that he handwrote over 30,000 thank-you notes to employees. And this set an example for other leaders. Leaders have about 400 of these touch points a day. Most don't take long, less than two minutes each. The key is to be agile and mindful in each of these moments. Civility lifts people. We'll get people to give more and function at their best if we're civil. Incivility chips away at people and their performance. It robs people of their potential, even if they're just working around it. What I know from my research is that when we have more civil environments, we're more productive, creative, helpful, happy and healthy. We can do better. Each one of us can be more mindful and can take actions to lift others up around us, at work, at home, online, in schools and in our communities. In every interaction, think: Who do you want to be? Let's put an end to incivility bug and start spreading civility. After all, it pays. Thank you. (Applause)
(Risas) Es fácil pensar así, sobre todo cuando vemos algunos ejemplos destacados que dominan la conversación. Bueno, resulta que a largo plazo no es así. Morgan McCall y Michael Lombardo investigaron profundamente el tema cuando estuvieron en el Centro de Liderazgo Creativo. Encontraron que la principal razón de los fracasos en las empresas es tener un trato insensible, brusco y acosador. Siempre habrá algunos casos atípicos que tienen éxito pese a su incivilidad. Pero, tarde o temprano, la mayoría de los irrespetuosos sabotean su propio éxito. A los jefes descorteses, por ejemplo, todo se les vuelve en contra si están en una posición vulnerable o si necesitan algo. La gente no los respalda. Pero ¿qué pasa con la gente amable? ¿Vale la pena ser cortés? Sí, claro que sí. Y ser cortés no solo significa que no eres un imbécil. Ayudar a una persona a superarse no es lo mismo que no retenerla. Ser realmente cortés es hacer pequeñas cosas, como sonreír y saludar en el pasillo o escuchar con atención cuando alguien habla contigo. Se pueden tener opiniones fuertes, discrepar, tener discusiones o hacer una crítica negativa, pero siempre con respeto. Algunos lo llaman "franqueza radical", que implica cuidar de la persona y a la vez hablarle francamente. Así que sí, ser cortés vale la pena. En una empresa de biotecnología, con mis colegas encontramos que aquellos considerados corteses duplicaban la posibilidad de ser vistos como líderes y su desempeño mejoraba notablemente. ¿Por qué vale la pena ser cortés? Porque la gente te ve como una combinación importante, poderosa y única de dos rasgos claves: afectuoso y competente, amigable e inteligente. En otras palabras, ser cortés no se trata solo de motivar a otros. Se trata de uno mismo. Si somos corteses, es más probable que seamos vistos como líderes. Nos desempeñaremos mejor, y nos verán afectuosos y competentes. Pero la cortesía tiene aún más ventajas que se relacionan con una de las preguntas más importantes sobre el liderazgo: ¿qué es lo que más espera la gente de sus líderes? Recabamos datos de 20 mil empleados en todo el mundo y encontramos una respuesta muy simple: respeto. Ser tratados con respeto es más importante que el reconocimiento y la apreciación, la crítica constructiva e incluso la oportunidad de aprendizaje. Las personas que se sienten respetadas están más sanas, prestan más atención, son más propensas a permanecer en su organización y están mucho más comprometidas. Entonces, ¿por dónde se empieza? ¿Cómo ayudamos a las personas a superarse y sentirse respetadas? Lo positivo es que no requiere de un gran cambio. Las pequeñas cosas hacen la diferencia. Comprendí que dar las gracias, compartir el mérito, escuchar con atención, preguntar con humildad, reconocer a los demás y sonreír tienen un gran impacto. Patrick Quinlan, exdirector de la empresa "Ochsner Health [System]" me contó sobre los efectos de su método "3 - 1": si uno se encuentra a tres metros de alguien, hace contacto visual y sonríe, y si está a poco más de un metro, saluda. Quinlan explicó que la cortesía se multiplicó, la satisfacción de los pacientes aumentó y la cantidad de nuevos pacientes también. La cortesía y el respeto pueden servir para aumentar el desempeño organizacional. Cuando mi amigo Doug Conant asumió como director general de "Campbell's Soup Company" en 2001, la empresa acababa de perder el 50 % de su cuota de mercado. Las ventas disminuían y muchos empleados acababan de ser despedidos. Uno de los directores de Gallup dijo que nunca habían encuestado una organización menos comprometida. Cuando Doug llegó al trabajo el primer día, notó que había una cerca con alambre de púas rodeando la oficina central. Había torres de control en el estacionamiento. Dijo que parecía una prisión de mínima seguridad. Era un ambiente tóxico. A los cinco años, Doug había revertido la situación. Y a los nueve años, batían récords de desempeño y acumulaban premios, incluyendo "mejor lugar para trabajar". ¿Cómo lo hizo? El primer día, Doug les dijo a sus empleados que pensaba exigirles altos estándares de desempeño, pero que lo harían a través del respeto. Hizo lo que predicó, y esperó lo mismo de sus líderes. Para Doug, todo era cuestión de ser firme con los estándares y bondadoso con las personas. Para él, se trataba simplemente de los puntos de contacto, las interacciones diarias que tenía con los empleados, sea en el pasillo, en la cafetería o en las reuniones. Si manejaba bien cada punto de contacto, los empleados se sentirían valorados. Otra forma en que Doug hizo a sus empleados sentirse valorados demostrándoles que les prestaba su atención fue escribir, de su puño y letra, más de 30 mil notas de agradecimiento. Y esto fue un ejemplo para otros líderes. Los líderes tienen unos 400 puntos de contacto como estos todos los días. La mayoría no lleva más de dos minutos. La clave es ser ágiles y considerados en cada uno de estos momentos. La civilidad eleva a las personas. Conseguiremos que la gente rinda más y dé lo mejor de sí, si somos corteses. La incivilidad debilita a las personas y disminuye su desempeño. Les quita el potencial tan solo con tenerla cerca en el entorno laboral. Lo que aprendí de mis estudios es que cuando estamos en ambientes cordiales somos más productivos, creativos, colaboradores, sanos y felices. Podemos mejorar. Cada uno de nosotros puede ser más consciente y puede actuar para ayudar a los demás a superarse, en el trabajo, en el hogar, en las redes, en la escuela y en nuestra comunidad. En cada interacción, piensen: ¿quién quiero ser? Terminemos con el virus de la incivilidad y empecemos a difundir la civilidad. Después de todo, vale la pena. Gracias. (Aplausos)